Sarvesh K. Tiwari

POWER BI & ANALYTICS LEAD

ktsarvesh79@gmail.com ≥

+91-9205305571

Vasundhara, Ghaziabad 9

SUMMARY

Having over 15 years of professional experience in the automation domain, Highly experienced in Analysis, Design, Development and Implementation. Gathering of reporting requirements and prepared interactive dashboards. Experience in Business Objects and set up of security model Troubleshooting issues, training and mentoring less experienced Business Objects users. Design and Development of data analytics' using Power BI, Excel, and VBA-Macros, MS Access, Tableau etc

OPERATIONS MANAGEMENT

Communications

Time management

Customer and personal service



Coordination

Team performance & appraisal review



EXPERIENCE

Assistant Manager (Analytics)

Genpact India Private Limited Apr 2022 - Present

- Designed and developed Power BI graphical and visualization solutions with business requirements
- Experience in providing technical guidance in the installation, configuration, upgrades and implementation of various ETL & BI products
- Experience in establishing and enterprise -wide data governance & Master Data Management framework, with a focus on improving data quality & security by creating new or upgrading existing organizational policies and standards.
- Identify root causes of problems. Analyzing both the and short term effects of solutions and develop workable solutions. Ability to manage multiple project tasks with changing priorities and deadlines
- Experience in dimensional data modelling Enterprise Master Data model to load data from multiple transactional systems
- consulting Experience in all phases of data warehouse development life cycle (SDLC) from gathering Business Requirements, Data Analysis, Data Blending, Development, Migration, Testing, Implementations and supports

Deputy Manager (Reporting & Business' Analytics) HCL Technologies LTD Oct 2018 - Apr 2022

- Collaborated with business users, collected requests, and updated the set of existing BI reports to accommodate business needs
- Extensive hands -on experience in several data flow transformation including Derived-column, slowly changing Dimension, Look up, Data Conversion, Conditional-Split techniques, Merge, Join, Union
- Created DAX Queries to generate computed Measures / Columns in Power BI
- Developed analysis reports and visualizations using DAX functions like Table function, aggregation functions and iteration functions
- Wrote calculated columns, Measures queries in power bi desktop to show good data analysis techniques
- Integrated custom visuals based on business requirements using Power BI desktop
- Worked on all type of transformation that are available in Power BI query editor

EXL Service.com(I)Pvt. Ltd Aug 2014 - Oct 2018

- Publish Power BI Reports in the required originations and made Power BI Dashboard available in Web Client and Mobile Apps
- Developed complex calculated measures using DAX
- Delivered BI reporting solutions in Power BI and Tableau
- Manage Power BI portal Data refresh/User management and set up gatewat data refresh
- Integrated custom visuals based on business requirements using Power BI desktop
- Converting all Excel reports into Power BI

Data Analyst

HCL Technologies LTD Sep 2013 - Aug 2014

- Generating forecast accuracy report for the client
- Designing and formulating new reports and creating interactive dashboards and visualizations as per the stakeholders requirements
- Recognizing and extracting critical indicators from large and complex data set and being able to interpret and express those indicators in a business context
- Responsible for end to end automation of the reports by creating VBA Macors and modifying existing macros as per the requiremnts
- Applying Time standard Monthly Reports, Quarterly Reports Annual Reports published by Revenue. Designed Dashboard Using Excel VBA Macro, Xcelsius
- Taking care of all reporting parts daily, weekly, monthly reports and distributing the reports to the External and Internal Clients

Senior Associate (MIS)

EXL Service.com(I)Pvt. Ltd Oct 2006 - Jul 2013

- Collating all the daily production trackers of all the associates on the daily basis and prepare agent productivity report
- Generating and maintaining daily, weekly and monthly production hours from the B-Prompt application
- Design and manage daily operation performance reports (OPS) from British Gas client
- Prepare the monthly stack ranking report to gause the agent level performance considering the various criteria
- Prepare monthly P4P (pay for Performance) for all the processes

EDUCATION Bachelor Degree

Alteryx

Bundelkhand University Jhansi Jul 1996 - Jul 1999

SKILLS	Power BI	••••	Python	••••
	Advance Excel	••••	Share Point	••••
	VBA Macro	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet$	CMS AVAYA	••••
	SQL Sewrver	\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet	Service Now	••••
	Tableau	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ \circ$	JIRA	• • • • •